If you were to go back to when you were in either high school
or college, what is the best piece of advice you tell your younger self?
I'd probably be a little bolder than I was, and I'd probably be a little bit more
confident in who I was to make certain that I always remain authentic to who I was.
I guess for you at a younger age, like you said being bolder, what would be the
importance of, I guess, taking more risks when you're younger that that may have had on your life?
I took risks, don't get me wrong, but I think when you're young and you don't have all the anchors that
you get over time, and I don't mean anchors in a bad way, but you have responsibilities the older you get.
When you're young is when you should be trying as many different things as you can try, and by
the way, do it in a very bold, audacious way, and to have the confidence to go do it.
I love that. And just a few more questions, but
what industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
I sold sneakers and t-shirts for a living.
So did you own your own company?
No, I worked for Nike.
And what were you doing exactly?
I did a little bit of everything from sales to
retail to product. I was ultimately the president of the company.
No way.
Way.
You were the president of Nike.
Yeah.
Oh my goodness, that's amazing.
That's why I saw the white whites there.
Yeah.
Do I know Phil Knight?
Yeah, I know him real well.
That's amazing. So as someone who's been an entrepreneur, what is
your best piece of advice to someone starting a business in 2022?
Super strong focus on the consumer. Who are you trying to serve, and what type of problems are
you trying to solve for those people, or what type of products are you trying to create for them?
But I think it all starts with having a really
super strong focus on the consumer you're trying to serve.
I guess another question would be, from what you've seen throughout your career, for younger people today especially, whether it's a
certain skill set or attribute for someone to possess when coming out of school or going out into the real world,
how can someone become financially successful?
How can someone become financially free in 2022?
First of all, here's what I would say. I'd say chase your dreams, get
involved with something that you're passionate about, and then try to solve a problem.
And remain curious, and if you do that, and you focus on a consumer, I think ultimately you're
going to find something that works that's going to help you find that financial stability that you desire.
And just two last questions. So for someone who's been a president and has overseen a company like
Nike, what have you seen throughout Nike that's really enabled them to really grow and scale their brand?
I guess, what is your advice to someone trying to scale
and grow their brand and build a business into a renowned company?
I think what great companies do, not just Nike, but
great companies, it comes back to what I've already said.
It's the consumer, in the case of Nike, it
was athletes. We served athletes. We listened to those athletes.
And the insights that they gave us, we translated
into innovative product that people coveted and desired and wanted.
And we told really emotional, cool stories that connected
the consumer to the brand and to those products.
And so I guess that is super sharp focus
on the consumer. That then translates into a great product.
And then you've got to tell emotional stories.
I love that. I love that.
It's real simple and logical.
I think sometimes we overcomplicate things.
And this is a fun one we've been
asking people, but I'm curious to get your answer.
But if you had to start from zero and you had one year to
make a million dollars and your life depended on it, what would you do?
A million dollars? Open a bar. No, I don't know.
Geez, that's a tough one. Life depended on it.
A GoFundMe page?
I would probably do that. I would definitely, hey,
my life depends on this. Help save me. How's that?
And with this one then, I guess, what has been the
worst and the best financial decision that you've made throughout your lifetime?
Best was, I had a plan.
When I started making enough money where
I actually, I had a plan in place.
I set goals out for myself
and I stuck with that plan.
So that's one of the things I would
say every young person is have a plan.
And I'd save 10% of my
income. There's stuff that you, it works.
That's what I'd say.
Worst, when you listen to someone tell
you, hey, there's this can't miss investment.
I've had a few of those
and I've missed almost every time.
I think if there's a can't
miss, it's probably because it's not true.
I made some, probably some silly
bets on some quote, can't miss investments.
And that's when you get off
track. Stay focused on your plan.
Thank you so much for your time.
Appreciate it.